# Jennifer Brana

☑ jbrana@cs.cmu.edu | 🎓 jenniferbrana.github.io | 🖸 JenniferBrana | 🛅 jenniferbrana

### Research Interests

I am interested in the intersection of hardware and software systems, particularly in the area of parallel computing and heterogeneous systems. My aim is to increase the scalability and sustainability of future computing systems.

Research areas: computer architecture; computer systems; memory systems; sustainability.

#### Education

**Carnegie Mellon University** 

Pittsburgh, PA

Ph.D in Computer Science

Beginning June 2023

Advisor: Nathan Beckmann **University of Portland** 

Portland, OR

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (3.9 GPA), Cum Laude

Aug. 2019 - May 2023

MINOR IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING.

# **Publications**

**Kobold: Simplified Cache Coherence for Cache-Attached Accelerators** 

IEEE CAL 2023

Jennifer Brana, Brian C. Schwedock, Yatin A. Manerkar, Nathan Beckmann

to appear

**Kobold: Simplified Cache Coherence for Cache-Attached Accelerators** 

WDDSA @ MICRO 2022

Jennifer Brana, Brian C. Schwedock, Yatin A. Manerkar, Nathan Beckmann

# Talks and Presentations

Kobold: Simplified Cache Coherence for Cache-Attached Accelerators

Kobold: Simplified Cache Coherence for Cache-Attached Accelerators

University of Portland Founders'

Comparison of Computer Architecture Specialization Methods for Performance and

**Power Efficiency** 

Day, 12 April 2022

WDDSA @ MICRO, 2 Oct. 2022

SRC @ MICRO, 3 Oct. 2022

# Professional Experience \_\_\_\_\_

#### **Carnegie Mellon University**

Pittsburgh, PA

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

June 2023 - Present

· Researching in computer architecture.

# **Computer Organization Research Group (CORGI)**

Carnegie Mellon University

Undergraduate Research Assistant

May 2022 - Present

• Research methods to design cache coherence protocols for cache-attached accelerators.

**Team Lift** Portland, OR; Karonga, Malawi

SENIOR CAPSTONE

Aug. 2022 - May 2023

• Deployed a connected network of sensors and computation nodes in an infrastructure-limited environment in Malawi, Africa.

**University of Portland** Portland, OR

Undergraduate Researcher

Jan. 2022 - May 2022

- · Investigated CPU specialization methods to increase the performance and efficiency of Viterbi Decoding.
- Simulated processor architecture using gem5 and modeled processor power consumption using McPat.

#### Intelligent, Complex, Adaptive, and Networks Lab

University of Portland

Undergraduate Research Assistant

May 2021 - August 2021

• Researched EEG-based view of comprehension of truth statements to understand how humans process undefined statements.

# Honors & Awards

NSF Graduate Research Fellowship, GRFP NSF

**CS Outstanding Student Award**, For combination of coursework, research, and service. U of Portland 2023

Tau Beta Pi Induction, National engineering honor society. 2020 U of Portland

2019-2023 President's Scholarship

U of Portland 2019-2023 FIRST Robotics Scholarship U of Portland

# Service & Leadership \_\_\_\_\_

Tau Beta Pi University of Portland

OREGON GAMMA CHAPTER PRESIDENT

2021 - 2022

• Responsible for planning meetings and activities to engage club members ranging from career development to design competitions.

#### **Society of Women Engineers**

University of Portland

MENTOR

2020 - 2023

• Mentored freshman girls in the engineering program.

#### **Tutoring Working Group**

University of Portland

STUDENT REPRESENTATIVE

· Worked with faculty members to redesign the tutoring program for the Shiley School of Engineering following the Covid-19 pandemic to increase freshman and sophomore retention rates.

# **Teaching**

#### **University of Portland**

Theory of Computation (CS 357) Grader, Fall 2022

Digital Systems Design (EE 332) Tutor, Spring 2022

Signals & Systems (EE 262) Tutor, Spring 2022

Logic Design (EE 231) Grader and Tutor, Fall 2021

Electrical Circuits (EE 261) Tutor, Fall 2021-Spring 2022

Electrical Circuits Lab (EE 271) Lab Assistant, Spring 2021

# Skills

**Programming Languages** C, C++, Python, Java, Assembly, MATLAB, Haskell, Verilog HDL, LaTeX **Parallel Programming** Experience in parallel/GPU computing using CUDA C/C++, OneTBB

**Computer Architecture Tools** Experience using gem5, SLICC, McPat, Murphi model checker, CACTI, ProtoGen/HieraGen

Proficiency with Unix, SSH, Git/Github, Xcode, VSCode. Experience in Agile